Hi, good day everybody, good morning, afternoon,
evening wherever you are in the world. I am
Dr. Suresh Venkatesan. I’m the chairman
and CEO of POET Technologies and I want to
provide you with a short update on on the
company and what we’ve achieved over the
past year. Let'’s see if I can get this
working. Have you used ChatGPT lately? Questions
like this signal the increasing presence of
AI in our tech-heavy world. AI, generative
AI, artificial intelligence is all the rage
these days. Do you know what the biggest challenge
with AI is today? It’s power, energy! I
was at a conference on this topic the other
day. Apparently the power required to program
the 175 billion parameters in ChatGPT runs
over a gigawatt! Just by contrast: The human
brain consumes 25 watts of power for similar
operations. That is quite a chasm to cross!
But one way to begin to address the power
challenge is to convert data transmission
to optics, data communications over optical
fiber, using light as the carrier dominates,
because it is 10 times faster, uses 10 times
less power and produces much less heat than
electrons flowing through copper. Nothing
else can do what photonics can do to increase
bandwidth and speed while reducing latency
and power consumption. So what does POET do?
POET makes optical modules that enable optical
data transmission. And this is fundamental
to scaling the presence of AI. Others make
optical modules as well. But POET has developed
unique intellectual property that allows us
to make these modules better, cheaper, lower
power and larger scale than anyone else. More
than cost or bill of sales it is the scale
where POET shines. And by scale we mean the
number of units that can be economically produced.
POET has semiconductorized photonics packaging
and put it squarely on the same trajectory
as semiconductors. Semiconductorization of
photonics using POET’s proprietary Optical
Interposer provides unprecedented scale and
economy for the rapidly growing AI and optical
communications market. In fact it's our belief
that it's not possible to address these markets
that need hundreds of millions or billions
of these devices any other way. Integration
is the key. Semiconductorization is the key.
And we believe we have pioneered this art
of semiconductorization of photonics packaging.
And that means terrific potential in a large
growing and increasingly relevant market in
AI and co-packaged optics. We have come a
long way over the past year with many accomplishments
under our belt. We serve a very large market
worth billions of dollars, particularly in
data communications and AI. We're squarely
in the supply chain for AI hardware. We have
a super unique and patented technology that
provides us with a source of sustained competitive
differentiation across a number of market
verticals including AI and high performance
computing. We have an exciting product roadmap,
born out of six years of technology and product
development. We've partnered with some of
the largest optical companies in the world,
like Lumentum, Broadcom, Macom. We have a
pipeline of customers across the world and
design wins that could total more than 150
million dollars of revenue over a three-year
period. We have a majority stake in a manufacturing
joint venture that could alone have an asset
value of over 200 million over the next two
to three years. The prime motivator for optics
and data communications and AI is power and
latency. Light as we have mentioned is 10x
faster and 10x lower power and has ruled the
roost when it comes to long distance data
communications. In fact, photonics 1.0 was
driven by submarine communications, long-distance
communications; use optics as the medium for
that communication to occur. However, as bandwidth
– meaning the amount of information that
is communicated per second – keeps increasing,
the distance over which this data is communicated
with light has become shorter and shorter.
Photonics 2.0, data centers, key driver for
optics. So optics is now in data centers,
is used for communications when distances
exceed about five meters. With AI, the bandwidth
and power crunch is so severe that there is
now a need to utilize optics as a means to
communicate data even between individual components,
like graphics and memory. The volume and scale
of these AI applications quickly trumps the
more conventional data center applications.
And the greater the need, the greater we feel
POET’s solutions in the space will begin
to gain favor. AI is the killer app for photonics
3.0. So the market for POET solutions spans
the more traditional data centers and data
communications which includes of course enterprise
and telecom applications and the new and emerging
market around AI-driven needs for optics.
In fact, we believe the AI-driven needs are
going to trump the more conventional data
center interconnects that has really been
kind of the prime driver for the past decade.
Both of these markets are large and growing.
They exceed 12 billion dollars in TAM by 2025.
The inflection point for growth in these markets
begins next year, and POET is well poised
with both solutions and customer access this
year. And we are well-positioned to intercept
this market at the right time with our differentiated
solutions. So the key challenges in photonics,
especially when it comes to very large scale
in terms of volume, is really the ability
to build millions, billions of these devices.
And conventional photonics packaging technology
simply will not fit the bill. I mean, those
solutions have been designed and have been
developed and honed over 30 years. But they
were first designed for single-channel applications.
Then they were designed for quad applications,
where the base technology was scaled through
engineering. But today, the applications demand
eight channels, 16 channels. They demand hundreds
of millions of units a year, not millions
of units a year. And there comes a point where
these conventional technologies simply cannot
fit the bill. Absolutely possible to engineer
in prototype quantities. But try to scale
that with good economies and economics! That's
where POET comes in. Our vision has always
been wafer-scale integration of known-good-die
components that address the pinch points of
volume, size, cost, power consumption. These
are the areas where we believe our technology
ticks the boxes – consistently –, and
that is the beauty of what POET has invented,
which is the Optical Interposer. The Optical
Interposer enables what we call chip-scale,
wafer-level packaging. In the world today,
in semiconductors, wafer-level, chip-scale
packaging is the norm. You look at your cell
phone, you look at these devices that are
in high-performance computing: They're all
built with wafer-level, chip-scale packaging,
where discrete electronics die are put together
into a chip-scale package. TSMC would call
that CoWoS. Intel calls it EMIB. But basically
it's wafer-level, chip-scale packaging. We're
the first company in the world to adapt wafer-level,
chip-scale packaging to photonics. So now,
instead of just integrating electronic die
we're able to mix and match photonics and
electronics die on a wafer-scale packaging
platform. That's what we call the POET Optical
Interposer. And we've been successfully deploying
these interposer-based solutions into a number
of products after basically having developed
the platform initially. The benefits to customers
are of course cost, size, scale, and power
consumption. We believe, especially as you
go forward in high-frequency data communications,
the RF performance benefits of an optical
interposer result ultimately in lower power
consumption. Of course there's the big conversion
of copper to optics and that is a big piece
of that too. More importantly, with the optical
interposers is that our customers who adopt
interposer-based engine solutions can lower
their CapEx bill by by a factor of 10, because
we do all the integration onto the optical
engine. That is kind of cut both ways for
us. You know, on the one hand new and upcoming
module makers that have not invested in that
CapEx really love it because they take advantage
of this huge reduction in CapEx from their
perspective to adopt our solutions, But on
the flip side bigger, larger, well-established
module makers that have already invested in
warehouses of capital and warehouses of people,
it's a little bit more difficult for them
to switch and adopt a solution that largely
eliminates a lot of their value, which is
putting it together by buying an integrated
solution from POET. So that has cut us both
ways. I mean, it's learning for us as we go
forward in our progress. But I think what
is clear is the value proposition that the
technology has overall, and that's the platform,
the technology that we've developed, which
also provides versatility for a number of
multiple applications. From a manufacturing
standpoint, we've established a joint venture.
We've worked with Sanan IC in 2019. It was
important for POET to ensure that there was
a high-volume manufacturing path for its optical
engine solutions. As a small company we leveraged
other people's money in this context. We created
a joint venture POET has not invested a dime
in creating this joint venture manufacturing
capability – not a dime. We've provided
know-how, no IP, and we've leveraged that
know-how to create a manufacturing asset,
a clean room, equipment, people. That's what
is required to ultimately scale up the technology.
And as a small company, we've been able to
leverage Sanan. Sanan is the world's largest
provider of compound semiconductors in terms
of LEDs. They recently launched a 3.2 billion
dollar joint venture with ST Microelectronics
to do silicon-carbide chips. I mean, these
guys know manufacturing. And they want this
joint venture to be successful, and they've
been investing into it. This joint venture
now takes our optical interposers and converts
them into optical engines through wafer-level
assembly techniques. And these optical engines
are then sold to optical module makers and
in some cases back to POET, where POET makes
the end module. A word on Super Photonics.
It's a latent value that we have created in
this company that we believe doesn't get enough
recognition for what we've been able to deliver.
There was a joint venture we formed in 2020
between POET and Sanan IC just as Covid was
breaking out. Its mission is to assemble,
test, package, and sell optical engines, based
completely on POET's optical interposal technology.
We formed the company in 2019, the Chinese
company. It was independently valued at 50
million US dollars at formation. For POET,
it enables a fab-light manufacturing model
with no investment by POET. We spent all our
cash on R&D. Somebody else is enabling us
to scale it into manufacturing. If POET ourselves
had to set up that manufacturing entity, we
would have had to raise so much more money
to be able to create this capability but we
didn't. We created a joint venture, we got
a partner involved, and they have now invested
10 million dollars and change. They're committed
to investing another 15 million dollars to
scale this up over the next six months. We've
employed 38 employees. They've been able to
take our technology prototypes that we've
developed in Singapore and demonstrate scale
and yield and capability that is truly impressive.
In fact, I was there six weeks ago, first
time ever since we formed the joint venture
as China is now opened up and and we're able
to travel freely with our old visas. Terrific
stuff! The goal for the Super Photonics joint
venture is the IPO in China in 2026/2027.
We currently own a 80 percent equity stake
in this joint venture. At the time of IPO,
we would probably be closer to 50 percent.
Even today, there is strong interest from
China-based PE firms in owning a piece of
Super Photonics. And valuations for photonics
in China are huge, valuations for photonics
in China for innovative technologies even
bigger, and once that innovative technology
starts turning revenue that valuation skyrockets.
We believe that this joint venture could be
worth over 200 million dollars in the next
couple to three years, as soon as Super Photonics
starts generating revenue in amount, which
we think will be in a couple of years. I mean,
that is just absolute latent value that we
have created and our ability to capture that
value is to be able to sell our equity stake
in that joint venture that provides a non-dilutive
source of financing for the company to do
other things: more R&D, more products. So
we think that we're sitting on really great
value. And I commend Vivek and team for their
efforts and being able to set this up and
for the the overall POET organization to support
creating what we believe is a very high-value
capability for the company going forward.
Our line of optical engines. This is what
they look like. If you guys have seen semiconductor
chips you will know what I'm talking about.
These are photonics sub-assemblies. They look
like semiconductor chips. On the left are
our 800G receivers as well as transmitters.
We announced just two weeks ago that we are
starting to sample our alphas of a 400G/800G
scalable transmitter, first of the kind in
the industry, first company to use DML lasers
and generate 400G/800G capability. In fact,
when we presented the data to Lumentum they
acknowledged that we're the first company
that they have sold these DML to that have
actually transformed these DMLs into a working
product. And we did prototypes at the OFC,
we are doing samples now and six months later.
We are well on track with our roadmap to be
able to take this into production early next
year. On the extreme right hand side, you
see our product. This is specifically for
DVA. Again, first of the kind in the world!
A full chip-on-board implementation of a 16-lane
architecture that fits inside of a QSFP-DD
form factor. It's a 16-lane product! ADVA
didn't have any other path to making this.
We were the only choice. They're actively
architecting this. They have a customer business
that is keenly awaiting this product to be
made available to them. And so we're stoked.
In this particular case we made this product
line happen through our innovation. And these
products are now ready and basically awaiting
ADVA to have their module design completed,
so that they can take it into production,
and there's obviously a lot of motivation
on their part to do that given the uniqueness
of the solution in the market. We're also
the first company to do wafer-level remote
laser solutions for co-packaged optics and
AI. Our product release plans for 2023 and
2024. We have come a long way. About a year
ago, we were demonstrating 100G products.
One year later, we're demonstrating 800 gigabit
products, sampling 800 gigabits today. We've
released our 100G receivers as well as transmitters,
and we have three additional variants on the
100G. One is what we call POET One or the
fully-integrated single-chip TXRX solution.
This is going to be a product that we're going
to take into the telecom market in China with
our customer BFYY and their end customers,
the likes of China Mobile. So that will be
released at the end of Q3. We also have LR4
products, not just the one we did for ADVA
but conventional LR4, that there are at least
four customers that were sampling to today.
Again, will be released in Q3. We completed
our beta for our 200G products. That'll be
released in Q3 as well. 400G receivers have
been released. 800G receivers and transmitters
end of the year. You can count the number
of products we're going to be releasing this
year. It is insane but it's possible because
of our our interposer technology the platform
approach, the fact that we use known good
components. And the moment we've been able
to ally with some of the top optical component
suppliers we've been able to demonstrate the
value that the engine provides in this context,
which is converting a DML laser into an engine,
with good RF in enhanced capability. And what
POET would like to do is to be able to generate
modules for 800G, which is critical not just
for data communications like custom modules
for 800G are also used extensively in AI.
On the other side, we have a set of remote
light source products that we are still developing.
I think our goal is to be able to really expand
our portfolio in the space with key investments
that we want to be able to make, where we
believe that we have the ability to really
make a a very meaningful contribution in this
growing market of artificial intelligence,
not just because we might have extremely differentiated
DML-based 800 gigabit modules but also very
differentiated remote light sources. We've
been really busy as a company. Year to date
in 2023, we've announced key engagements with
customers: ADVA, Luxshare. Luxshare is a billion
dollar company. They sell primarily to Apple
and others, and they've got a business and
an access to the hyperscale market. We're
designed-in already with their 800 gigabit
solutions with our receivers. In fact, we've
gotten initial yields, these are sample-quantity
POs which is common early in the development
where we provide engines for them to be able
to develop their modules. BFYY: our first
foray into telecom. the exposure into a really
large market there, which are the mobile players,
the big mobile players, and the telecom stakes
in China. The POET Infinity product line:
We announced our engagement with Celestial
with this new class of products for their
applications. We've received the purchase
order from them for supplying product next
year. And we also announced some product announcements
around the lines of Infinity, announced the
availability of these products sampling of
800G. It it's been a busy year, and we expect
that as we release more products over the
next couple of quarters to be able to announce
additional customers, additional engagements,
and we do believe that we can keep up with
what needs to be done in terms of kind of
gaining traction and gaining engagement around
this platform. We have 11 current projects
with seven key customers, and just these projects
represent a combined 150 million dollars of
revenue potential over three years – just
these projects, nothing new. But we do expect
something new. We've got another a bunch of
products that we're planning to release over
the course of the next couple of months, and
we do believe that when those products are
released there will be more take up, more
engagements. But based on what our customers
tell us about these products and when they
intend to ramp and their potential forecasts
for these products, we estimate that for POET
and Super Photonics this can be a cumulative
150 million dollars of revenue potential.
So, if they're successful, we're going to
be successful, too. And it's important for
us to project and plan because we need to
have the manufacturing capability to be able
to deliver this. And that's where Super Photonics
comes in, and that's where the additional
investments from Sanan are going to be placed.
Today, our technology and business strategy
is fundamentally centered around building
interposers and optical engines and providing
expertise to end customers or module makers
providing finished modules. While we believe
that this is a reasonable model for kind of
the legacy, if you will, or 100G to 200G to
400G, especially in the AI segment we think
we have to transcend beyond the optical engine
and create optical modules. So, the future
for POET is to actually create optical modules,
and we believe we can do that because a big
portion of the optical module is already factored
into the engine. We've integrated tiers, we've
integrated drivers, we've got very good RF
capability on the interposer, we've got all
the photonics components on the interposer,
we create effectively everything except the
DSP. So our intent is to add a third set of
capabilities for design and development of
these optical modules. We're already doing
it for AI. It's a critical requirement for
AI. So our intent in AI is clearly to have
optical modules generated. So, that doesn't
mean that we're going to stop selling engines
to module makers. I think in the advanced
technology, specifically for AI, our intent
would be to create optical modules. It enables
the sale of our leading edge products directly
to the end customer without having to go through
this middleman and this long process of getting
designed-in and the iterations associated
with more development to be done along the
way. It reduces time to market, eliminates
qualification cycles. We think it's the right
thing to do. It requires some investment,
and we're looking at an alternate joint venture
capability that allows us to potentially fund
this activity. Again, raising money with some
non-dilutive financing here. In 2020, when
we created the joint venture in China, China
was in fashion. We were complimented for having
done that. Today, I read the boards and of
course everybody barfs on the fact that we
have manufacturing in China. But it is important
to understand that it is a very, very, very
large market. It is in fact the largest market
for optics, 100 to 400 gigabits per second.
But we recognize that things have changed.
There are geopolitical issues. There is likely
to be more and more constraints – and high-end
in AI and AI solutions, and so we intend to
create an alternate joint venture outside
of China and follow what we would call a “China
plus one” strategy, which a lot of customers
require or demand, where we have a foot in
china to support kind of the Chinese market
with China components, and then we have kind
of the ability to be able to manufacture outside
of China as well. So we're actively seeking
as i said an additional JV partner to provide
a source of independent financing for this.
This is critical to POET's future. And we
believe we can be very, very successful in
this endeavor. I'm sorry, my ability to move
the slides is somewhat delayed. We've done
a fair bit on the investor outreach front.
Our goal was to increase awareness
of POET, so audience is likely to invest, with
a focus on the U.S. We've taken various steps
to do that, some popular, some not so popular,
but the results speak for themselves. We've
had a 300 percent growth in monthly website visits
from December to June – a 100 percent month
over month visit growth from May. 3:1 U.S. visitors
to canadian visitors, which was a big thing.
We wanted to get more presence in the
U.S. Our Nasdaq volumes are finally higher than
TSX venture and has been up since December.
So we will continue to attack and adapt, of
course. Not everything that we do
works beautifully. We have a path, we have a
vision, we want to get something done, but,
as with everything else, you have to attack
and adapt, and we are. But the results speak
for themselves and we will continue to drive
this, going forward.
So, in summary, we've created an innovative
patented optoelectronic integration platform
technology. We believe we're the only known
technology that can meet the vectors of volume,
size, cost, power, for future photonics products,
especially in large, high-growth markets, including
datacom, telecom, and AI hardware. We are partnered
with some of the leading companies in the
optical communications supply chain. We're
engaged with several key customers now. That
allows us to demonstrate the technical acceptance
of our solution. I mean, we are, after all, doing
something that has not been done before. We
are, after all, creating products are that are
first of its kind in the industry and there's
some degree of healthy skepticism about whether
we can actually do it and that's skepticism
first is can it be done technically then it's
can it actually meet specs and then it's can
you actually scale this in volume and we're
going through that process super photonics
is critical to enable market acceptance of
our optical engine products we're doing that
today they're ramping up we have a revenue
pipeline on customer engagements that provide
150 million dollars of three-year estimated
revenues based on their projections to us
of course there's no guarantees but you know
they know their business they know their customers
and they believe that they can represent us
what it would mean to us with this engagement
we expect revenue to begin in 2024 but of
course we will have production orders this
year we already do for the first half of next
year three million dollars from the fyy we
expect pos this year as well in fact super
photonics does have evos but like i said these
are quantities that enable our customers to
design their modules in although our engines
are ready you know we can't ramp into production
until our customer or so in this case super
photonics this customer can ramp their solution
and in some cases there have been some delays
because they have never used optical engines
before and so it's a learning process for
them as well so we kind of go through that
i mean it's you know there there are changes
and and to our roadmap sometimes out of our
control you know our products are ready and
available and sampling and providing to the
customers and then we just have to work through
the process of getting them designed in and
i think we're the likes at the end of the
tunnel we can see it we've we work with these
customers and and we do believe over the next
couple of quarters that um that we should
or super photonics should be able to start
start their ramp right and most significantly
we've created a significant value capture
potential with super photonics in terms of
its asset appreciation and what that can mean
to poet in terms of non-diluted financing
the company we need it right we need the financing
to be able to keep our roadmap to drive our
leadership in a sense in the ai space to really
take advantage of our existing position and
grow it and and we think that this is a very
very critical piece of you know how how that
can happen in in the long term so with that
you know let me close and and i thank you
for your time i thank you for your attention
i thank you for your support go put i hand
it over to you at this point all right i'll
jump in i think uh suresh with some questions
uh from uh from the from the group at uh gopode
indeed uh tell us what your objectives were
with the atm or aftermarket financing that
was announced this morning oh sorry um i think
i was i might have met him been on mute uh
can you repeat that because it just didn't
come through clearly on my end sure uh tell
us what your objectives were with the atm
or the at the market financing that was announced
this morning oh yeah the the atm or at the
market program you know it gives port management
the flexibility to raise capital in small
amounts over the course of the next year um
i think there's uh a lot of misunderstandings
um associated with the mechanics of how atm
works so i will shortly kind of ask tom to
maybe step in and and paint some color and
and provide some some guidance there um but
as as the atm itself it's the least costly
method for the company to raise capital in
the public markets low commissions compared
to public offerings no warrants attached you're
basically selling shares at market price no
discounts so the atm programs have been common
among issues in the united states for several
years and have become much more popular now
recently in canada and we believe that an
atm is an essential part of a financing strategy
of a high growth technology-based company
but you know the mechanics of the atm is i
guess misunderstood and um so perhaps tom
you might want to take a few minutes to explain
how the mechanics work sure i'd be happy to
suresh thank you uh what i want to emphasize
first is is that this is not a 30 million
dollar financing that we're doing today or
any time in the in the near future it's very
much misunderstood as being that it's a facility
that allows us the company to sell shares
at the market price and we're it's a heavily
regulated transaction so we're we have to
be cautious about whether our intervention
or our sale of shares into that market moves
the market so we're intending over the course
of the next 12 months to take advantage of
high volume days in which we believe we can
sell co-chairs at a reasonable and appropriate
price and the way that that happens is the
there were two investment banks uh that were
named in the prospectus one is craig hallam
in the united states who many of you know
uh follows us through richard shannon uh their
analysts in the optics area and in canada
core mark that has been an investment bank
for us for a couple of transactions few transactions
over the past couple of years so i have access
to a particular trader at each of those desks
and we convene early in the morning and see
what the market activity is going to be project
what we think the market activity may be during
the week and we determine at that time whether
or not we're going to be selling any shares
into the market we are totally in control
of the price at which we sell shares and the
number of shares that we sell and so having
that kind of facility around allows us to
raise capital in the public market as suresh
said at the lowest cost it's a three percent
commission rather than a seven percent commission
and there are no warrants and it's at the
market so we're not really you know competing
against um others to to who want to buy or
sell our shares so it's important to remember
that this is a facility that we have that
will completely in control of it's been very
common as suresh said in the united states
for a long time among most issuers and in
canada because they've relaxed the rules somewhat
over the last two years it's becoming more
common and i think you'll see it in many other
issuers uh up in canada so we're going to
be we're going to be looking at both markets
over time and as i said we're um we have to
be very cautious about not moving the market
in any way and i'm sure that the regulators
will be watching that over the course of the
next 12 months um okay so thank you thanks
uh tom thanks uh suresh on on giving us some
background on that uh following on the same
topic how does the company plan to fund itself
for the next six to 12 months while ramping
production and does the company need or plan
to raise additional capital before the end
of 2023 beyond what you've already mentioned
yeah i put current stage we're continuously
evaluating the capital required to operate
the business and execute on our ongoing strategic
initiatives um as part of this process we're
actively considering several potential alternatives
non-dilutive means of bringing in additional
capital as mentioned in the presentation we
believe that our equity in spx is a valuable
asset that is not obvious in our financial
statements and we have been approached by
private equity companies interested in owning
a piece of that operation which both jv partners
believe is a good prospect for an ipo in china
so once spx begins to generate revenue we
expect its value to increase exponentially
in addition in connection with our plan to
sell modules we believe that there are good
opportunities to form additional joint ventures
um if you were to create a new jv for module
production we would expect to structure it
uh in a way to both provide capital to pull
it and also to allow us to consolidate its
results in our financial statements okay and
um moving on to a question on some of our
early adopters our early customers uh when
uh when do we expect to be in production or
have receive initial orders from adva and
fiber top for some of the poet legacy that
um they're contracting as i said i mean you
know i think initial orders we've had it we've
delivered it that cx has rather um you know
i think the the key thing is you know how
quickly can they complete their module design
and um and it's gone through some iterations
um you know these are these are companies
i mean not used to working with optical engines
in the case of our advert it's it's uh i mean
like i said 16 channels in a case of pdd never
been done before um so they're going through
some learning curves on their end right our
designs are complete the products ready um
but we believe they're closed and and they
do have an end market that they can sell them
to their customers are waiting so there's
motivational and best of interest of the part
of them to finish their module design we expect
that this happens over the course of this
quarter uh honestly um i think now that we
have the ability to travel to china and i
believe roger is there next week you know
we're going to be able to get much better
engagement with them and you know hasten their
development in the case of fiber top for example
but but i mean they're engaged we've got weekly
meetings um it's hard to project and predict
exactly when they're gonna rank you know i
mean this is this has been our challenge as
well and that you know our products ready
uh we will release it at the end of this coming
quarter and kill three but does that mean
it ramps immediately probably not but it's
not very far and and for sure it's not a question
of if and when but but rather when the opportunity
is there the value potential is there um we
just need to we need our customer in a sense
um to begin their ramp which which we do expect
uh to happen in 24 with like i said initial
production will start at the end of this year
but but really the the meaningful production
will be in 2024. um but that's you know largely
given their schedule right i mean it's it's
it's hard for us to kind of really push that
on on our end uh aggressively i think the
best we can do is to release the product and
have it available and you know work with them
closely which is what the team's doing um
to enable their design to be completed okay
terrific uh on to a couple of questions or
back to the stock price as a topic uh two
questions on that what strategy is being employed
to attract new institutional investors and
what gives you the confidence it will be effective
look i mean over the past 18 months i think
it's yeah about about the time we kind of
moved to the nasdaq um or about the time russia
in the end of ukraine whichever way you look
at it um we have participated in nine wall
street focused conferences targeted at institutional
retail investors in the us we have we remain
engaged with and distribute all announced
business developments with a sizable number
of institutional investor targets which are
continuing to follow poet's progress we've
also stayed actively engaged with multiple
south side research analysts including our
existing covering analysts such as richard
richard shannon at greg hallo who initiated
last year and has continued to provide forward
with much broader exposure is highly recognized
in the industry he covers momentum and some
of the larger companies right so he knows
what he's talking about and i think he's respected
and recognized additionally we have been driving
increased visibility through participation
and presentations and industry trade shows
i think just this week we had a a video that
was actually in chinese created by mo you
know that that got a lot of inbound traction
um when it was published at the industry trade
show there so this all contributes to elevated
awareness not just among customers but but
also tech oriented investors okay and what
else is the company doing to increase the
current uh share price look at shareholders
ourselves um we're always looking at new ways
to support our stock price and attract new
investors our top priority as a management
team is to create shareholder value through
continued execution on our business plan and
begin generating a sustainable and growing
revenue stream to the extent that we are successful
in capturing even a portion of the available
market opportunity we believe the stock price
will ultimately reflect that value appropriately
to help further expand our investor outreach
efforts in january we retain stockhouse to
help execute an advertising and marketing
campaign that has seen increased interest
through website visitation as well as expanded
awareness via newsletters and digital marketing
then in april we engaged he capital markets
for distribution of our company's content
on investors hub and wall street silver services
we also continue to actively participate in
wall street focused events conferences speaking
opportunities the one thing i'd like to point
out is that poetstalk is up what over 40 year
to date and even over the past 12 months we've
kind of meaningfully outperformed a large
majority of publicly traded micro cap tech
companies it's not been an easy market folks
um but you know there's there's still just
satisfaction obviously and um you know but
what we can do is is manage what is on our
control and that is execute our roadmap which
we've been doing and you've seen it you know
we've provided our roadmap and we periodically
give you updates and we're on track and what
do you think uh then suresh based on this
activity that poets valuation should be now
based on the progress that you've outlined
what we've made this year i i don't think
it's an it's it's my job to comment on on
valuations so i i don't think i'm going to
answer that question okay and let's uh let's
have one here on uh when can we expect to
see additional buying and or exercising of
warrants by insights look i mean i think most
of the warrants are are done there's probably
a single crunch of warrants left in august
um so yeah i mean i think uh you know i i
like like i said i don't i don't control what
other management members of the board do in
poet we're all independent um folks um so
yeah i i don't think there's uh a lot more
warrants left honestly to be exercised than
we we'd like to keep it that way going forward
too okay and and with the stock trading where
it is today how committed is management and
the board to resisting a potential unsolicited
buyer to offer at an attractive valuation
oh um and you know look uh our our interest
is is in building you know long-term shareholder
value and um and so you know i think we're
uh we recognize and understand the value we
bring and we recognize and understand the
value um that is achievable and so you know
i don't think this is a concern that existing
shareholders need to have i think you know
we all collectively are vested in doing what
is necessary to drive uh shareholder value
at valuations that we believe uh accurately
represents uh what we offer uh in the industry
right and what we offer to this large and
growing market uh especially in ai okay and
we have a question here um about uh competitors
both uh well let's go within nvidia are they're
currently the kings of the ai market how could
poet uh enhance their offering look i think
you know and i mean nvidia the kings and the
ai market because they create uh you know
highly parallel computing infrastructure with
their gpus and then you know they tie it up
with with large amounts of memory and and
sell these pgx boxes at 30 40 000 a pop um
but you know i think going forward i mean
you know i think data center servers are going
to incorporate in video graphics processors
and so on and so forth so yes they're they're
they're a graphics company there are kings
there um i think how poet helps is uh is by
providing you know the means to communicate
either between graphics and memory or by providing
the means to communicate between servers um
and you know today much of that is done either
by you know 800 gig and a transceiver modules
they look like transceiver modules but they're
kind of custom specifically for ai um or um
they can take the form of photonic fabrics
um and and other such uh applications that
there are other companies kind of driving
and so so the ai segment is kind of bifurcated
right one is there's just a growth or a need
for a lot of optics and that is bifurcated
into kind of transceiver like form factors
which we plan to and then into photonic fabric
like form factors with new companies and upcoming
companies that again we play into by providing
remote light sources so i think we're um we're
well covered uh in terms of what we can do
and um and are actively working to intercept
this very large growth market over the next
couple of years okay of the 11th current uh
contracted uh projects that you uh stated
uh having today which one or two represent
the largest near-term revenue opportunities
i guess this is specifically with our products
and our customers and what are the remaining
steps to convert these opportunities into
revenue well i mean i think for most part
these are committed projects i mean i think
we're going through the development phases
in the case of companies like celestial and
their projected volumes to us i mean you know
those are products that are committed and
we have pos we have to deliver all the teams
working on you know finishing up that design
by the end of this year and you know we have
a po to deliver a certain number of those
uh engines by by the end of 2024 for you know
kind of a larger ramp next year um turn most
of those except for one i believe uh which
is still um you know in evaluation by the
customer um there are commitments to use the
products they are designed in so then it's
it's not to me a question of if then it's
a question of when that when depends less
on poet's readiness and more on our customers
you know ability to convert that into a module
design and then ultimately take it and and
be successful in the market um but you know
on a balance you know i think we're well positioned
there with with a really good potential okay
and uh regarding air labs do you view them
as a competitor or a potential partner neither
i view them as a as a customer a potential
customer um i mean they they are one of the
companies that have a photonics fabric um
they also require a remote light source and
we believe we have a good technical solution
um and uh there have been dialogues and discussions
and we hope at some point that we can convert
that opportunity into into you know a real
engagement uh and with uh uh sticking with
the products and uh the uh optical interposer
how far behind are competitors to what the
optical interposer can do i'm sorry i think
you have to repeat that question please how
far behind are the competitors to uh the optical
interposer and what it's able to deliver to
the market look i mean i have yet to see i
mean i've said this publicly before i think
the only company that had you know capability
uh or at least a vision are very similar to
what poet was discussing and talking about
was rock lee photonics um you know they ultimately
were not successful in creating these products
and data communications i mean we've we've
successfully sampled 800 gig receivers because
it's i mean you know we we we've done we've
come a long ways relative to what others thought
they could do but couldn't ultimately do it
um now outside of them i'm not seeing too
many single things sorry uh no that's good
that's uh uh regarding the light bar have
other companies tested the light bar family
products and how are those samples um being
received and can we expect future announcements
there's a little bit of i mean ambiguity among
the customer base especially as it relates
to copaceted optics or um or remote blazers
um it is a very very custom market it's a
kind of a wild west right now there's no there's
no kind of standards um you know what our
labs uses is something completely different
what celestial wants is something completely
different what light matter uses something
completely different like the legends is completely
different they're all different right and
so what you know um in in a sense it plays
to our strength because we've got a platform
we have the ability to adopt these solutions
um but you know it's also difficult because
we keep sampling and talking to customers
and they change their requirements and needs
sometimes it's four channels it grows to eight
and it's 12 and um so yeah i think you know
well the good thing is we've got the right
products and we've got the relationships and
the engagement uh and we do believe that you
know as those requirements and needs develop
and coalesce into something uh we will have
the solutions available for them um but um
today our primary focus is you know ensure
a successful deployment on celestial ai i
mean honestly uh if they are half as successful
as they think they're going to be and have
represented in their uh forecast that i'm
sure you can read up um you can see how lucrative
just simply that is going to be for this company
um and then you add one or two i think the
intent is really not to go we're not here
trying to get numbers in terms of customers
we're trying to get wins win with the winners
right and and and we think if we can you know
just convert a couple of them um these are
really really large opportunities ahead of
us and i've got one here on uh that's i know
the the team is excited about the this application
with film thin film lithium nibate uh can
you comment on on that and how's that progressing
future you know the important thing is that
we have the ability to to incorporate new
and upcoming components onto our interposer
uh but look i mean you know 10 from lithium
live here is not going to be ready for prime
time in terms of kind of commercial volumes
for it for it's at least three years um so
you know i think it's it's it's something
that we're engaged with in this case you know
um liabate on and and we're working with them
in parallel but you know we've also got a
focus on products that you know we know are
imminently required um so we are you know
initiating our development programs around
a 200 gig per lane eml based solutions that
those are the most mature solutions for 200
gigabit per lane today um lithium-908 will
be there at some point but you know i think
we we need to we need to work with components
that are ready today um and and leverage them
fast and rapidly you know and not keep betting
the form on some future um i think we made
that mistake a year and a half ago with so
you know waiting for a silicon photonics modulator
to be available and we lost a year on our
roadmap and i don't think we're ready to make
that mistake again uh no certainly not and
lots lots going on with with the company and
that i don't see any more questions uh ceresha
i'm just going to throw it back to you for
some closing remarks yeah well i mean you
know it's uh it's been a it's been a an exciting
year so far um you know we've we've got a
lot of work ahead of us for sure um you know
we've had shareholders um that have either
express good satisfaction or dissatisfaction
and i'm hoping that we can all coalition around
the fact that you know we over the past five
years have developed something that is new
that is unique um you know we're committed
as a team to drive progress we're committed
as a team to ensure success um and and we
do believe that you know um we've got as a
company the the the products to be able to
leverage this um you know new and rapidly
growing area of ai which is going to provide
tremendous opportunity to everybody in photonics
uh including poet right and and so and you
know the good thing is we're well positioned
to capitalize on it because it kind of plays
to our strengths um so i'm i'm kind of stoked
about that looking forward to the future uh
and as always thank you for your continued
support very good uh thank you suresh i really
appreciate the comments that uh you made and
we appreciate the videos that were shown i
am sure the shareholders and participants
and guests also appreciate what was uh disclosed
and reported here today so again we want to
express our gratitude to um everyone who's
participated and thank you to the lumi platform
for making this available to us today ladies
and gentlemen we've come to the end of the
meeting again we want to extend our gratitude
to you for your continued support and we look
forward to joining with you again at future
meetings please have yourselves a good safe
and enjoyable canada day long weekend and
july 4th long weekend thank you all I am Dr.
Suresh Venkatesan. I’m the chairman and
CEO of POET Technologies and I want to provide
you with a short update on on the company
and what we’ve achieved over the past year.
Let'’s see if I can get this working. Have
you used ChatGPT lately? Questions like this
signal the increasing presence of AI in our
tech-heavy world. AI, generative AI, artificial
intelligence is all the rage these days. Do
you know what the biggest challenge with AI
is today? It’s power, energy! I was at a
conference on this topic the other day. Apparently
the power required to program the 175 billion
parameters in ChatGPT runs over a gigawatt!
Just by contrast: The human brain consumes
25 watts of power for similar operations.
That is quite a chasm to cross! But one way
to begin to address the power challenge is
to convert data transmission to optics, data
communications over optical fiber, using light
as the carrier dominates, because it is 10
times faster, uses 10 times less power and
produces much less heat than electrons flowing
through copper. Nothing else can do what photonics
can do to increase bandwidth and speed while
reducing latency and power consumption. So
what does POET do? POET makes optical modules
that enable optical data transmission. And
this is fundamental to scaling the presence
of AI. Others make optical modules as well.
But POET has developed unique intellectual
property that allows us to make these modules
better, cheaper, lower power and larger scale
than anyone else. More than cost or bill of
sales it is the scale where POET shines. And
by scale we mean the number of units that
can be economically produced. POET has semiconductorized
photonics packaging and put it squarely on
the same trajectory as semiconductors. Semiconductorization
of photonics using POET’s proprietary Optical
Interposer provides unprecedented scale and
economy for the rapidly growing AI and optical
communications market. In fact it's our belief
that it's not possible to address these markets
that need hundreds of millions or billions
of these devices any other way. Integration
is the key. Semiconductorization is the key.
And we believe we have pioneered this art
of semiconductorization of photonics packaging.
And that means terrific potential in a large
growing and increasingly relevant market in
AI and co-packaged optics. We have come a
long way over the past year with many accomplishments
under our belt. We serve a very large market
worth billions of dollars, particularly in
data communications and AI. We're squarely
in the supply chain for AI hardware. We have
a super unique and patented technology that
provides us with a source of sustained competitive
differentiation across a number of market
verticals including AI and high performance
computing. We have an exciting product roadmap,
born out of six years of technology and product
development. We've partnered with some of
the largest optical companies in the world,
like Lumentum, Broadcom, Macom. We have a
pipeline of customers across the world and
design wins that could total more than 150
million dollars of revenue over a three-year
period. We have a majority stake in a manufacturing
joint venture that could alone have an asset
value of over 200 million over the next two
to three years. The prime motivator for optics
and data communications and AI is power and
latency. Light as we have mentioned is 10x
faster and 10x lower power and has ruled the
roost when it comes to long distance data
communications. In fact, photonics 1.0 was
driven by submarine communications, long-distance
communications; use optics as the medium for
that communication to occur. However, as bandwidth
– meaning the amount of information that
is communicated per second – keeps increasing,
the distance over which this data is communicated
with light has become shorter and shorter.
Photonics 2.0, data centers, key driver for
optics. So optics is now in data centers,
is used for communications when distances
exceed about five meters. With AI, the bandwidth
and power crunch is so severe that there is
now a need to utilize optics as a means to
communicate data even between individual components,
like graphics and memory. The volume and scale
of these AI applications quickly trumps the
more conventional data center applications.
And the greater the need, the greater we feel
POET’s solutions in the space will begin
to gain favor. AI is the killer app for photonics
3.0. So the market for POET solutions spans
the more traditional data centers and data
communications which includes of course enterprise
and telecom applications and the new and emerging
market around AI-driven needs for optics.
In fact, we believe the AI-driven needs are
going to trump the more conventional data
center interconnects that has really been
kind of the prime driver for the past decade.
Both of these markets are large and growing.
They exceed 12 billion dollars in TAM by 2025.
The inflection point for growth in these markets
begins next year, and POET is well poised
with both solutions and customer access this
year. And we are well-positioned to intercept
this market at the right time with our differentiated
solutions. So the key challenges in photonics,
especially when it comes to very large scale
in terms of volume, is really the ability
to build millions, billions of these devices
and conventional photonics packaging technology
simply will not fit the bill. I mean, those
solutions have been designed and have been
developed and honed over 30 years. But they
were first designed for single-channel applications.
Then they were designed for quad applications,
where the base technology was scaled through
engineering. But today the applications demand
eight channels, 16 channels. They demand hundreds
of millions of units a year, not millions
of units a year. And there comes a point where
these conventional technologies simply cannot
fit the bill. Absolutely possible to engineer
in prototype quantities. But try to scale
that with good economy! Economies and economics
– that's where POET comes in. Our vision
has always been wafer-scale integration of
known-good-die components that address the
pinch points of volume, size, cost, power
consumption. These are the areas where we
believe our technology ticks the boxes – consistently.
And that is the beauty of what POET has invented,
which is the Optical Interposer. The Optical
Interposer enables what we call chip-scale,
wafer-level packaging. In the world today
in semiconductors, wafer-level, chip-scale
packaging is the norm. You look at your cell
phone, you look at these devices that are
in high-performance computing. They're are
all built with wafer-level, chip-scale packaging,
where discrete electronics die are put together
into a chip-scale package. TSMC would call
that CoWoS, Intel calls it EMIB, but basically
it's a wafer-level, chip-scale packaging.
We're the first company in the world to adapt
wafer-level, chip-scale packaging to photonics.
So, now, instead of just integrating electronics
die, we're able to mix and match photonics
and electronics die on a wafer-scale packaging
platform. That's what we call the POET Optical
Interposer, and we've been successfully deploying
these interposer-based solutions into a number
of products, after basically having developed
the platform initially. The benefits to customers
are of course in cost, size, scale, and power
consumption. We believe, especially as you
go forward in high-frequency data communications,
the RF performance benefits. Often Optical
Interposer result ultimately in lower power
consumption. Of course there's the big conversion
of copper to optics, and that is a big piece
of that too. More importantly, with the Optical
Interposer is that our customers who adopt
interposer-based engine solutions can lower
their CapEx bill by by a factor of 10 because
we do all the integration onto the optical
engine. That is kind of cut both ways for
us. On the one hand, new and upcoming module
makers that have not invested in that CapEx
really love it because they take advantage
of this huge reduction in capex from their
perspective to adopt our solutions but on
the flip side you know bigger larger well-established
module makers that have already invested in
warehouses of capital and warehouses of people
um it's a little bit more difficult for them
to switch right and continue and adopt a solution
that largely eliminates a lot of their value
which is putting it together by buying an
integrated solution from poet so so that has
cut us both ways i mean it's it's it's learning
for us as we go forward you know in our progress
right uh but i think what is clear is is the
value proposition that the technology has
overall um and that's the platform the technology
that we've developed which also provides versatility
uh for a number of multiple applications from
a manufacturing standpoint um we've established
a joint venture we worked with china and i
see in 2019 um it was important for poet to
ensure that there was a high volume manufacturing
path for its optical engine solutions as a
small company we leveraged other people's
money in this context we created a joint venture
poor did not has not invested a dime in creating
this joint venture manufacturing capability
not a dime we've provided know-how no ip and
we've leveraged that know-how to create a
manufacturing asset a clean room equipment
people that's what's required to ultimately
scale up the technology and as a small company
we've been able to leverage sina and sana
is the world's largest provider of compound
semiconductors in terms of leds they recently
launched a 3.2 billion dollar joint venture
with sd microelectronics to do silicon carbide
chips i mean these guys know manufacturing
and and they want you know this joint venture
to be successful and they've been investing
into it this joint venture now takes our optical
interposers and converts them into optical
engines through wafer level assembly techniques
and these optical engines are then sold the
optical module makers and in some cases back
to port where poet makes the end module a
word on super photonics it's it's it's a latent
value that we have created in this company
that we believe doesn't get enough recognition
for what we've been able to deliver uh there
was a joint venture we formed in 2020 uh between
poet and sinai c just as covet was breaking
out the submission is to assemble best package
and sell optical engines is completely on
poet's optical interposal technology we formed
the company in 2019 the chinese company it
was independently valued at 50 million us
dollars at formation for poet it enables a
fab light manufacturing model with no investment
by part i mean we spent all our cash on r
d somebody else is enabling us to scale it
into manufacturing if four of them ourselves
we had to set up that manufacturing entity
we would have had to raise so much more money
to be able to create this capability but we
didn't we created a joint venture we got a
partner involved and they have now invested
10 million dollars and change they're committed
to investing another 15 million dollars to
scale this up over the next six months we've
employed 38 employees they've been able to
take our technology prototypes that we've
developed in singapore and demonstrate scale
and yield and and capability that that it's
truly impressive in fact i was there uh what
six weeks ago first time ever uh since we
formed the joint venture um as as china has
now opened up and and we're able to travel
freely with our old visas terrific stuff the
goal for the super photonics joint venture
is the ipo in china in 2026 2027. uh we currently
own a 80 equity stake in this joint venture
at the time of ipo we would probably be closer
to 50 percent even today there is strong interest
from china-based pe firms and owning a piece
of super photonics and valuations for photonics
in china are huge valuations for photonics
in china for innovative technologies even
bigger and once that innovative technology
starts turning revenue that valuation skyrocket
we believe that this joint venture could be
worth 200 over 200 million dollars in the
next couple to three years as soon as super
photonics start generating revenue insignificant
in an amount which we think will be in a couple
of years i mean that is just absolute latent
value that we have created and our ability
to capture that value is to be able to sell
our equity stake in that joint venture that
provides a non-dilutive source of financing
for the company to do other things more r
d more products so we think that you know
we're sitting on um on on really great value
and you know i commend the vacant team uh
for their efforts and being able to set this
up and and and and for the the overall poet
organization to support creating what we believe
is a very high value um capability for the
company going forward our line of optical
engines i mean this is what they look like
uh if you guys have seen semiconductor chips
you will know what i'm talking about these
are photonics sub-assemblies they look like
semiconductor chips on the left or our 800
gig receivers as well as transmitters we announced
just two weeks ago that we are starting to
sample our alphas of a 400 800 gig scalable
transmitter first of the kind in the industry
first company to use dml lasers and generate
400 gig 800 gig capability in fact when we
presented the data to momentum they acknowledged
that we're the first company that they have
sold these dml to that have actually transformed
these dmls into a working product for the
and we did prototypes at the ofc we are doing
samples now and six months later well on track
one with our roadmap to be able to take this
into production early next year on the extreme
right hand side you see our product this is
specifically for adverb again first of the
kind in the world a full chip on board implementation
of a 16 lane architecture that fits inside
of a qsfpdd form factor it's a 16 lane product
didn't have any other path to making this
we were the only choice they're actively architecting
this they have a customer business that is
keenly awaiting this product to be made available
to them and so we're stoked i mean we're in
this particular case we we made this product
line happen through our innovation and these
products are now ready and basically a waiting
advert to have their module design completed
so that you know they can take it into production
and there's obviously a lot of motivation
on their part to do that given um the uniqueness
of the solution in the market we're also the
first company to do wafer level remote laser
solutions for co-packaged optics and ai our
product release plans for 2023 and 2024 we
we have come a long way about a year ago we
were demonstrating 100 gig products one year
later we're demonstrating 800 gigabit products
sampling 800 gigabits today we've released
our 100 gig receiver as well as transmitters
and we have three additional variants on the
100 gig one is the what we call poet one or
the fully integrated single chip pxrx solution
this is going to be a product that we're going
to take into the telecom market in china with
our customer bfyy and their end customers
the likes of china mobile and so that will
be released at the end of q3 we also have
lr4 products not just the one we did for advert
but you know conventional lr4 uh that there
are at least four customers that were sampling
to today again will be released in q3 we completed
our beta for our 200 gig products that'll
be released in q3 as well 400 gig really receivers
have been released 800 gig receivers and transmitters
end of the year you can count the number of
products we're going to be releasing this
year it is insane but it's possible because
of you know our our interposer technology
the platform approach the fact that we use
known good components and the moment we've
been able to ally with some of the top optical
component suppliers we've been able to demonstrate
the value that the engine provides in this
context which is converting a dml laser into
an engine with good rf right in enhanced capability
and what poet would like to do is to be able
to generate modules for three 800 gig which
is critical not just for data communications
like custom modules for in 800 gig are also
used extensively in ai on the other side we
have you know a set of remote light source
products that we are still developing i mean
i think our goal is to be able to really expand
our portfolio in the space with key investments
that we want to be able to make where we believe
that we have the ability to really make a
a very meaningful contribution in this growing
market of artificial intelligence not just
because we might have extremely differentiated
dml based 800 gigahertz modules but also very
differentiated remote light source we've been
really busy as a company year to date in 2023
we've announced key engagements with customers
adverb lux share luxury is a billion dollar
company right they sell primarily to apple
and others and they've got a business and
an access to the hyperscale market we're designed
in already with their 800 gigabit solutions
with our receivers in fact we've gotten initial
fields right these are sample quantity pos
which which is which is common uh early in
the in the in the development where we provide
engines for them to be able to develop their
modules bfyy our first foray into telecom
the exposure into a really large market there
which are the mobile players the big mobile
players and the telecom states in china the
poet infinity product line we announced our
engagement with celestial with this new class
of products for their applications we've received
the purchase order from them for supplying
product next year and we also announced some
product announcements right around the lines
of infinity announced the availability of
these products sampling of 800 gig it it's
been a busy year and and we expect you know
that as we release more products over the
next couple of quarters to be able to announce
additional customers additional engagements
and and we do believe that we can keep up
with what needs to be done in terms of kind
of gaining traction and gaining engagement
around this this platform we have 11 current
projects with seven key customers um and just
these projects represent a combined 150 million
dollars of revenue potential over three years
just these problems nothing new but we do
expect something new right we've got another
a bunch of products that we're planning to
release over the course of the next couple
of months and we do believe that when those
products are released there will be more take
up more engagements right but based on what
our customers tell us about these products
and when they intend to rev and their potential
forecasts for these products we estimate that
for poet and super photonics this can be a
cumulative 150 million dollars of revenue
potential right so they're successful we're
going to be successful too and it's important
for us to project and plan because we need
to have the manufacturing capability to be
able to deliver this and that's where super
photonics comes in and that's where the additional
investments from santa are going to be placed
today our technology and business strategy
is fundamentally centered around building
interposers and optical engines and providing
expertise to end customers or module makers
provide finished modules why we believe that
this is a reasonable model for kind of the
legacy if you will or 100 gigs or 200 gigs
or 400 gigs especially in the ai segment you
know we think we have to transcend beyond
the optical engine and create optical modules
so the future for poet is to actually create
optical modules and we believe we can do that
because a big portion of the optical module
is already factored into the engine we've
integrated tiers we've integrated drivers
we've got very good rf capability on the interposer
we've got all the photonics components on
the interposer we create effectively everything
except the dsp so our intent is to add a third
set of capabilities for design and development
of these optical modules uh we're already
doing it for ai it's a critical requirement
for ai so our intent in ai is clearly to have
optical modules generated so it doesn't mean
that we're going to sell engines to module
makers i think in the advanced technology
specifically for ai our intent would be to
create optical modules it enables the sale
of our leading edge products directly to the
end customer without having to go through
this middleman and this long process of getting
designed in and the iterations associated
with more development to be done along the
way it reduces time to market eliminates qualification
cycles we think it's the right thing to do
it requires some investment and we're looking
at a you know an alternate joint venture capability
that allows us to potentially fund this activity
again you know raising money with some non-diluted
financing here in 2020 when we created the
joint venture in china you know china was
in fashion i mean we were complemented for
having done that you know today i read the
boards and you know of course everybody barfs
on the fact that we have manufacturing in
china but it is important to understand that
it is a very very very large market it is
in fact the largest market for optics 100
to 400 gigabits per second but we recognize
that things have changed um there are geopolitical
issues um there is likely to be more and more
constraints and high-end in ai nai solutions
and so we intend to create an alternate joint
venture outside of china and follow what we
would call a china plus one strategy which
a lot of customers require or demand where
we have a foot in china to support kind of
the chinese market with china components and
then we have kind of you know the the ability
to to be able to manufacture outside of china
as well so we're actively seeking as i said
an additional jv partner to provide a source
of independent financing for this this is
critical to poet's future and we believe we
can be very very successful in this endeavor
i'm sorry my uh ability to move the slides
is somewhat delayed uh we've done a fair bit
on the investor outreach front um you know
our goal was to increase awareness of put
so audience is likely to invest with a focus
on the u.s we've taken various steps to do
that some popular some not so popular but
the results speak for themselves we've had
a 300 growth and monthly website visits from
december to june a hundred percent month over
month visit growth from may 31 u.s visitors
to canadian visitors which was a big thing
right we wanted to get more presence in the
us our nasdaq volumes are finally higher than
psx venture and has been up since december
so we will continue to attack and adapt of
course you know not everything that we do
works beautifully we have a path we have a
vision we want to get something done but you
know as with everything else you have to attack
and adapt and we are but but the results speak
for themselves and we will continue to drive
this going forward so in summary we've created
an innovative patented optoelectronic integration
platform technology we believe we're the only
known technology that can meet the vectors
of volume size cost power for future photonics
products especially in large high growth markets
including datacom telecom and ai hardware
we are partnered with some of the leading
companies in the optical communications supply
chain we're engaged with several key customers
now that allows us to demonstrate the technical
acceptance of our solution i mean we are after
all doing something that has not been done
before we are after all creating products
are that are first of its kind in the industry
and there's some degree of healthy skepticism
about whether we can actually do it and that's
skepticism first is can it be done technically
then it's can it actually meet specs and then
it's can you actually scale this in volume
and we're going through that process super
photonics is critical to enable market acceptance
of our optical engine products we're doing
that today they're ramping up we have a revenue
pipeline on customer engagements that provide
150 million dollars of three-year estimated
revenues based on their projections to us
of course there's no guarantees but you know
they know their business they know their customers
and they believe that they can represent us
what it would mean to us with this engagement
we expect revenue to begin in 2024 but of
course we will have production orders this
year we already do for the first half of next
year three million dollars from the fyy we
expect pos this year as well in fact super
photonics does have evos but like i said these
are quantities that enable our customers to
design their modules in although our engines
are ready you know we can't ramp into production
until our customer or so in this case super
photonics this customer can ramp their solution
and in some cases there have been some delays
because they have never used optical engines
before and so it's a learning process for
them as well so we kind of go through that
i mean it's you know there there are changes
and and to our roadmap sometimes out of our
control you know our products are ready and
available and sampling and providing to the
customers and then we just have to work through
the process of getting them designed in and
i think we're the likes at the end of the
tunnel we can see it we've we work with these
customers and and we do believe over the next
couple of quarters that um that we should
or super photonics should be able to start
start their ramp right and most significantly
we've created a significant value capture
potential with super photonics in terms of
its asset appreciation and what that can mean
to poet in terms of non-diluted financing
the company we need it right we need the financing
to be able to keep our roadmap to drive our
leadership in a sense in the ai space to really
take advantage of our existing position and
grow it and and we think that this is a very
very critical piece of you know how how that
can happen in in the long term so with that
you know let me close and and i thank you
for your time i thank you for your attention
i thank you for your support go put i hand
it over to you at this point all right i'll
jump in i think uh suresh with some questions
uh from uh from the from the group at uh gopode
indeed uh tell us what your objectives were
with the atm or aftermarket financing that
was announced this morning oh sorry um i think
i was i might have met him been on mute uh
can you repeat that because it just didn't
come through clearly on my end sure uh tell
us what your objectives were with the atm
or the at the market financing that was announced
this morning oh yeah the the atm or at the
market program you know it gives port management
the flexibility to raise capital in small
amounts over the course of the next year um
i think there's uh a lot of misunderstandings
um associated with the mechanics of how atm
works so i will shortly kind of ask tom to
maybe step in and and paint some color and
and provide some some guidance there um but
as as the atm itself it's the least costly
method for the company to raise capital in
the public markets low commissions compared
to public offerings no warrants attached you're
basically selling shares at market price no
discounts so the atm programs have been common
among issues in the united states for several
years and have become much more popular now
recently in canada and we believe that an
atm is an essential part of a financing strategy
of a high growth technology-based company
but you know the mechanics of the atm is i
guess misunderstood and um so perhaps tom
you might want to take a few minutes to explain
how the mechanics work sure i'd be happy to
suresh thank you uh what i want to emphasize
first is is that this is not a 30 million
dollar financing that we're doing today or
any time in the in the near future it's very
much misunderstood as being that it's a facility
that allows us the company to sell shares
at the market price and we're it's a heavily
regulated transaction so we're we have to
be cautious about whether our intervention
or our sale of shares into that market moves
the market so we're intending over the course
of the next 12 months to take advantage of
high volume days in which we believe we can
sell co-chairs at a reasonable and appropriate
price and the way that that happens is the
there were two investment banks uh that were
named in the prospectus one is craig hallam
in the united states who many of you know
uh follows us through richard shannon uh their
analysts in the optics area and in canada
core mark that has been an investment bank
for us for a couple of transactions few transactions
over the past couple of years so i have access
to a particular trader at each of those desks
and we convene early in the morning and see
what the market activity is going to be project
what we think the market activity may be during
the week and we determine at that time whether
or not we're going to be selling any shares
into the market we are totally in control
of the price at which we sell shares and the
number of shares that we sell and so having
that kind of facility around allows us to
raise capital in the public market as suresh
said at the lowest cost it's a three percent
commission rather than a seven percent commission
and there are no warrants and it's at the
market so we're not really you know competing
against um others to to who want to buy or
sell our shares so it's important to remember
that this is a facility that we have that
will completely in control of it's been very
common as suresh said in the united states
for a long time among most issuers and in
canada because they've relaxed the rules somewhat
over the last two years it's becoming more
common and i think you'll see it in many other
issuers uh up in canada so we're going to
be we're going to be looking at both markets
over time and as i said we're um we have to
be very cautious about not moving the market
in any way and i'm sure that the regulators
will be watching that over the course of the
next 12 months um okay so thank you thanks
uh tom thanks uh suresh on on giving us some
background on that uh following on the same
topic how does the company plan to fund itself
for the next six to 12 months while ramping
production and does the company need or plan
to raise additional capital before the end
of 2023 beyond what you've already mentioned
yeah i put current stage we're continuously
evaluating the capital required to operate
the business and execute on our ongoing strategic
initiatives um as part of this process we're
actively considering several potential alternatives
non-dilutive means of bringing in additional
capital as mentioned in the presentation we
believe that our equity in spx is a valuable
asset that is not obvious in our financial
statements and we have been approached by
private equity companies interested in owning
a piece of that operation which both jv partners
believe is a good prospect for an ipo in china
so once spx begins to generate revenue we
expect its value to increase exponentially
in addition in connection with our plan to
sell modules we believe that there are good
opportunities to form additional joint ventures
um if you were to create a new jv for module
production we would expect to structure it
uh in a way to both provide capital to pull
it and also to allow us to consolidate its
results in our financial statements okay and
um moving on to a question on some of our
early adopters our early customers uh when
uh when do we expect to be in production or
have receive initial orders from adva and
fiber top for some of the poet legacy that
um they're contracting as i said i mean you
know i think initial orders we've had it we've
delivered it that cx has rather um you know
i think the the key thing is you know how
quickly can they complete their module design
and um and it's gone through some iterations
um you know these are these are companies
i mean not used to working with optical engines
in the case of our advert it's it's uh i mean
like i said 16 channels in a case of pdd never
been done before um so they're going through
some learning curves on their end right our
designs are complete the products ready um
but we believe they're closed and and they
do have an end market that they can sell them
to their customers are waiting so there's
motivational and best of interest of the part
of them to finish their module design we expect
that this happens over the course of this
quarter uh honestly um i think now that we
have the ability to travel to china and i
believe roger is there next week you know
we're going to be able to get much better
engagement with them and you know hasten their
development in the case of fiber top for example
but but i mean they're engaged we've got weekly
meetings um it's hard to project and predict
exactly when they're gonna rank you know i
mean this is this has been our challenge as
well and that you know our products ready
uh we will release it at the end of this coming
quarter and kill three but does that mean
it ramps immediately probably not but it's
not very far and and for sure it's not a question
of if and when but but rather when the opportunity
is there the value potential is there um we
just need to we need our customer in a sense
um to begin their ramp which which we do expect
uh to happen in 24 with like i said initial
production will start at the end of this year
but but really the the meaningful production
will be in 2024. um but that's you know largely
given their schedule right i mean it's it's
it's hard for us to kind of really push that
on on our end uh aggressively i think the
best we can do is to release the product and
have it available and you know work with them
closely which is what the team's doing um
to enable their design to be completed okay
terrific uh on to a couple of questions or
back to the stock price as a topic uh two
questions on that what strategy is being employed
to attract new institutional investors and
what gives you the confidence it will be effective
look i mean over the past 18 months i think
it's yeah about about the time we kind of
moved to the nasdaq um or about the time russia
in the end of ukraine whichever way you look
at it um we have participated in nine wall
street focused conferences targeted at institutional
retail investors in the us we have we remain
engaged with and distribute all announced
business developments with a sizable number
of institutional investor targets which are
continuing to follow poet's progress we've
also stayed actively engaged with multiple
south side research analysts including our
existing covering analysts such as richard
richard shannon at greg hallo who initiated
last year and has continued to provide forward
with much broader exposure is highly recognized
in the industry he covers momentum and some
of the larger companies right so he knows
what he's talking about and i think he's respected
and recognized additionally we have been driving
increased visibility through participation
and presentations and industry trade shows
i think just this week we had a a video that
was actually in chinese created by mo you
know that that got a lot of inbound traction
um when it was published at the industry trade
show there so this all contributes to elevated
awareness not just among customers but but
also tech oriented investors okay and what
else is the company doing to increase the
current uh share price look at shareholders
ourselves um we're always looking at new ways
to support our stock price and attract new
investors our top priority as a management
team is to create shareholder value through
continued execution on our business plan and
begin generating a sustainable and growing
revenue stream to the extent that we are successful
in capturing even a portion of the available
market opportunity we believe the stock price
will ultimately reflect that value appropriately
to help further expand our investor outreach
efforts in january we retain stockhouse to
help execute an advertising and marketing
campaign that has seen increased interest
through website visitation as well as expanded
awareness via newsletters and digital marketing
then in april we engaged he capital markets
for distribution of our company's content
on investors hub and wall street silver services
we also continue to actively participate in
wall street focused events conferences speaking
opportunities the one thing i'd like to point
out is that poetstalk is up what over 40 year
to date and even over the past 12 months we've
kind of meaningfully outperformed a large
majority of publicly traded micro cap tech
companies it's not been an easy market folks
um but you know there's there's still just
satisfaction obviously and um you know but
what we can do is is manage what is on our
control and that is execute our roadmap which
we've been doing and you've seen it you know
we've provided our roadmap and we periodically
give you updates and we're on track and what
do you think uh then suresh based on this
activity that poets valuation should be now
based on the progress that you've outlined
what we've made this year i i don't think
it's an it's it's my job to comment on on
valuations so i i don't think i'm going to
answer that question okay and let's uh let's
have one here on uh when can we expect to
see additional buying and or exercising of
warrants by insights look i mean i think most
of the warrants are are done there's probably
a single crunch of warrants left in august
um so yeah i mean i think uh you know i i
like like i said i don't i don't control what
other management members of the board do in
poet we're all independent um folks um so
yeah i i don't think there's uh a lot more
warrants left honestly to be exercised than
we we'd like to keep it that way going forward
too okay and and with the stock trading where
it is today how committed is management and
the board to resisting a potential unsolicited
buyer to offer at an attractive valuation
oh um and you know look uh our our interest
is is in building you know long-term shareholder
value and um and so you know i think we're
uh we recognize and understand the value we
bring and we recognize and understand the
value um that is achievable and so you know
i don't think this is a concern that existing
shareholders need to have i think you know
we all collectively are vested in doing what
is necessary to drive uh shareholder value
at valuations that we believe uh accurately
represents uh what we offer uh in the industry
right and what we offer to this large and
growing market uh especially in ai okay and
we have a question here um about uh competitors
both uh well let's go within nvidia are they're
currently the kings of the ai market how could
poet uh enhance their offering look i think
you know and i mean nvidia the kings and the
ai market because they create uh you know
highly parallel computing infrastructure with
their gpus and then you know they tie it up
with with large amounts of memory and and
sell these pgx boxes at 30 40 000 a pop um
but you know i think going forward i mean
you know i think data center servers are going
to incorporate in video graphics processors
and so on and so forth so yes they're they're
they're a graphics company there are kings
there um i think how poet helps is uh is by
providing you know the means to communicate
either between graphics and memory or by providing
the means to communicate between servers um
and you know today much of that is done either
by you know 800 gig and a transceiver modules
they look like transceiver modules but they're
kind of custom specifically for ai um or um
they can take the form of photonic fabrics
um and and other such uh applications that
there are other companies kind of driving
and so so the ai segment is kind of bifurcated
right one is there's just a growth or a need
for a lot of optics and that is bifurcated
into kind of transceiver like form factors
which we plan to and then into photonic fabric
like form factors with new companies and upcoming
companies that again we play into by providing
remote light sources so i think we're um we're
well covered uh in terms of what we can do
and um and are actively working to intercept
this very large growth market over the next
couple of years okay of the 11th current uh
contracted uh projects that you uh stated
uh having today which one or two represent
the largest near-term revenue opportunities
i guess this is specifically with our products
and our customers and what are the remaining
steps to convert these opportunities into
revenue well i mean i think for most part
these are committed projects i mean i think
we're going through the development phases
in the case of companies like celestial and
their projected volumes to us i mean you know
those are products that are committed and
we have pos we have to deliver all the teams
working on you know finishing up that design
by the end of this year and you know we have
a po to deliver a certain number of those
uh engines by by the end of 2024 for you know
kind of a larger ramp next year um turn most
of those except for one i believe uh which
is still um you know in evaluation by the
customer um there are commitments to use the
products they are designed in so then it's
it's not to me a question of if then it's
a question of when that when depends less
on poet's readiness and more on our customers
you know ability to convert that into a module
design and then ultimately take it and and
be successful in the market um but you know
on a balance you know i think we're well positioned
there with with a really good potential okay
and uh regarding air labs do you view them
as a competitor or a potential partner neither
i view them as a as a customer a potential
customer um i mean they they are one of the
companies that have a photonics fabric um
they also require a remote light source and
we believe we have a good technical solution
um and uh there have been dialogues and discussions
and we hope at some point that we can convert
that opportunity into into you know a real
engagement uh and with uh uh sticking with
the products and uh the uh optical interposer
how far behind are competitors to what the
optical interposer can do i'm sorry i think
you have to repeat that question please how
far behind are the competitors to uh the optical
interposer and what it's able to deliver to
the market look i mean i have yet to see i
mean i've said this publicly before i think
the only company that had you know capability
uh or at least a vision are very similar to
what poet was discussing and talking about
was rock lee photonics um you know they ultimately
were not successful in creating these products
and data communications i mean we've we've
successfully sampled 800 gig receivers because
it's i mean you know we we we've done we've
come a long ways relative to what others thought
they could do but couldn't ultimately do it
um now outside of them i'm not seeing too
many single things sorry uh no that's good
that's uh uh regarding the light bar have
other companies tested the light bar family
products and how are those samples um being
received and can we expect future announcements
there's a little bit of i mean ambiguity among
the customer base especially as it relates
to copaceted optics or um or remote blazers
um it is a very very custom market it's a
kind of a wild west right now there's no there's
no kind of standards um you know what our
labs uses is something completely different
what celestial wants is something completely
different what light matter uses something
completely different like the legends is completely
different they're all different right and
so what you know um in in a sense it plays
to our strength because we've got a platform
we have the ability to adopt these solutions
um but you know it's also difficult because
we keep sampling and talking to customers
and they change their requirements and needs
sometimes it's four channels it grows to eight
and it's 12 and um so yeah i think you know
well the good thing is we've got the right
products and we've got the relationships and
the engagement uh and we do believe that you
know as those requirements and needs develop
and coalesce into something uh we will have
the solutions available for them um but um
today our primary focus is you know ensure
a successful deployment on celestial ai i
mean honestly uh if they are half as successful
as they think they're going to be and have
represented in their uh forecast that i'm
sure you can read up um you can see how lucrative
just simply that is going to be for this company
um and then you add one or two i think the
intent is really not to go we're not here
trying to get numbers in terms of customers
we're trying to get wins win with the winners
right and and and we think if we can you know
just convert a couple of them um these are
really really large opportunities ahead of
us and i've got one here on uh that's i know
the the team is excited about the this application
with film thin film lithium nibate uh can
you comment on on that and how's that progressing
future you know the important thing is that
we have the ability to to incorporate new
and upcoming components onto our interposer
uh but look i mean you know 10 from lithium
live here is not going to be ready for prime
time in terms of kind of commercial volumes
for it for it's at least three years um so
you know i think it's it's it's something
that we're engaged with in this case you know
um liabate on and and we're working with them
in parallel but you know we've also got a
focus on products that you know we know are
imminently required um so we are you know
initiating our development programs around
a 200 gig per lane eml based solutions that
those are the most mature solutions for 200
gigabit per lane today um lithium-908 will
be there at some point but you know i think
we we need to we need to work with components
that are ready today um and and leverage them
fast and rapidly you know and not keep betting
the form on some future um i think we made
that mistake a year and a half ago with so
you know waiting for a silicon photonics modulator
to be available and we lost a year on our
roadmap and i don't think we're ready to make
that mistake again uh no certainly not and
lots lots going on with with the company and
that i don't see any more questions uh ceresha
i'm just going to throw it back to you for
some closing remarks yeah well i mean you
know it's uh it's been a it's been a an exciting
year so far um you know we've we've got a
lot of work ahead of us for sure um you know
we've had shareholders um that have either
express good satisfaction or dissatisfaction
and i'm hoping that we can all coalition around
the fact that you know we over the past five
years have developed something that is new
that is unique um you know we're committed
as a team to drive progress we're committed
as a team to ensure success um and and we
do believe that you know um we've got as a
company the the the products to be able to
leverage this um you know new and rapidly
growing area of ai which is going to provide
tremendous opportunity to everybody in photonics
uh including poet right and and so and you
know the good thing is we're well positioned
to capitalize on it because it kind of plays
to our strengths um so i'm i'm kind of stoked
about that looking forward to the future uh
and as always thank you for your continued
support very good uh thank you suresh i really
appreciate the comments that uh you made and
we appreciate the videos that were shown i
am sure the shareholders and participants
and guests also appreciate what was uh disclosed
and reported here today so again we want to
express our gratitude to um everyone who's
participated and thank you to the lumi platform
for making this available to us today ladies
and gentlemen we've come to the end of the
meeting again we want to extend our gratitude
to you for your continued support and we look
forward to joining with you again at future
meetings please have yourselves a good safe
and enjoyable canada day long weekend and
july 4th long weekend thank you all.